Guide to the Jim Neu Papers MSS.332
Fales Library and Special Collections
Jim Neu Papers
1960-2012
1972-2010
Fales Library and Special Collections
Mullins, Carol
Neu, Jim
MSS.332
22.03 Linear Feet in 24 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 6 cassette boxes, 4 record cartons, 1 oversized folder, 11 folders in a shared flat box, and 21 folders housed across 3 shared oversize boxes
133.25 Gigabytes in 671 digital files
190 audiocassettes
82 VHS
6 Hi8
28 U-matic
1 sound tape reels
8 MiniDV
5 Sound_Disc-MiniDisc
Jim Neu (1943-2010) was an American playwright and actor, based in New York City, who was best known for his experimental plays. The Jim Neu Papers (1960-2012) contain materials created and collected by Neu and focus largely on his theatrical career. Materials include drafts and finished copies of plays and screenplays; drafts of unfinished plays; promotional materials for his works such as posters, flyers, performance cards, and programs; photographs and slides of performances; audiocassettes, video tapes, and digital copies of Neu's productions; correspondence and reviews; research materials for Neu's plays; and administrative papers such as performance logistics, finances for his plays, and grant funding. The collection also contains materials related to writing workshops, personal correspondence, notebooks, agenda books, and the works of some of Neu's colleagues.
Biographic Note
Jim Neu (1943-2010) was an American playwright and actor, based in New York City, who was best known for his experimental plays. Neu was born in Brooklyn on November 18, 1943. He graduated from the State University of New York at Oneonta in the early 1960s and was then drafted into the U.S. Army. Instead of being sent to fight in Vietnam, Neu was stationed in Korea. After being discharged in 1967, he moved to Manhattan's Lower East Side and between 1970 and 1975, Neu performed with Robert Wilson's Byrd Hoffman School of Byrds.
In 1976, Neu briefly re-located to California and alongside his friend and collaborator, sk dunn, he began creating works for the Napa Valley Theater Company (NVTC). While at the NVTC, Neu also collaborated with composer Michael Galasso and choreographer Liz Pasquale. Together they created one of Neu's notable plays, Echo Ranch, in 1977. This piece was later performed at the Green St. Gallery and PS 1 in New York City.
Neu returned to New York City in the late 1970s and began to collaborate with several downtown Manhattan performance spaces including the Kitchen, the Westbeth Theater, PS122's Avant-Garde-Arama, and the Soho Reperatory Theatre. He also began to participate in theater festivals in both the United States and in Europe. In 1991, Neu became friends with Ellen Stewart, founder of the La MaMa Experimental Theater Club, and began his long-term working relationship with La MaMa.
Over the course of his career, Neu wrote many plays including Him or Me (1979), Basic Behavior (1982), Duet for Spies (1987), The Floatones (1995), Mondo Beyondo (1997), and Target Audience (2003) -- many of which were staged at La MaMa. He also wrote screenplays for two films, Doomed Loved (1983) and The Big Blue (1988), both of which were directed by Andrew Horne and premiered at the Berlin Film Festival.
Between 1985-1987, Neu was the receipient of a National Endowment for the Arts Fellowship and a New York Foundation for the Arts Playwriting Fellowship. In 1994 he was awarded a New Works grant by the New York State Council on the Arts and spent time at Andy's Summer Playhouse in New Hampshire mentoring young playwrights. In 2000, he was awarded an Arts International performance grant for the Exodus Festival in Lljubljana, Slovenia and conducted a playwriting workshop at the Mladinsko Theater.
Jim Neu died on July 19, 2010 from lung cancer.
Scope and Contents
The Jim Neu Papers (1960-2012) contain materials created and collected by Neu and focus largely on his theatrical career. The collection contains documents relating to many of Neu's plays including: Echo Ranch (1977), Aerobia (2001), Basic Behavior (1982), An Evening with Jesse James (1988), Him or Me (1979), Duet for Spies (1987), The Floatones (1995), Mondo Beyondo (1997), Mutual Narcissism (1984), Live Witness (1992), Kiss Shot (2002), Target Audience (2003), Optissimo Lounge (1991), La Vie Noir (2007) and more. The collection also contains documents relating to Neu's two films Doomed Loved (1983) and The Big Blue (1988).
These materials include drafts and finished copies of plays and screenplays; drafts of unfinished of plays; promotional materials for his works such as posters, flyers, performance cards, programs; print and digital photographs, as well as slides of performances; recordings of Neu's productions; correspondence and reviews; research materials for Neu's plays; and administrative papers such as performance logistics, finances for his plays, and grant funding. Together, these materials demonstrate Neu's active participation within the experimental theater community, the types of theatrical productions he participated in as an actor and playwright, his artistic style, and the venues he had relationships with in New York City and beyond.
The collection also contains the works of some of Neu's friends and collaborators including sk dunn, Mike Galasso, Andrew Horne, Ed Leighton, John Nesci, and Lenny Pickett.
Neu was heavily influenced by jazz music and often incorporated elements of it into his works. To this effect, the collection contains research materials focused on jazz and musicians including Duke Ellington. In addition to jazz recordings, the collection contains audiocassettes and videocassettes with interviews, music, and sound effects that were most likely used in Neu's performances. All of these have been listed with the original titles found on their containers.
In addition to Neu's plays, the collection contains materials related to writing workshops he participated in both domestically and internationally; notebooks, and agenda books; and personal correspondence. These materials represent Neu's life outside of his plays.
Arrangement
The materials in the collection are arranged in a single file listing with all material listed alphabetically by topic.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Carol Mullins in 2012. The accession number associated with this collecton is 2012-332.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
New York (N.Y.).; Experimental theater -- 21st century.; Plays (performed works); Photographs.; Notebooks; Correspondence.; Posters.; Video tapes.; Audiovisual materials.; Audiocassettes.; Promotional materials; Scripts.; Film.; Mullins, Carol; Neu, Jim
- 4 Dead Poets 10 New Poems, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Aerobia, 2001; cuid39244 (Box 1, Folder 2, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0066, 332.0086, Box 32, Vhs 332.0220, 332.0236, 332.0249, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_1)
- Airtime, undated (Box 32, Vhs 332.0254-332.0255, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 14)
- Alice in Wonderland (not produced, unfinished), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Alone Together, 2004-2005; cuid39245 (Box 1, Folder 4-5, Box 32, Vhs 332.0218, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_2)
- Alternate Merge, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The America Hour, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7-8, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 15)
- Andy Horn scenes 2+3 35 sec. lapse, undated (Box 34, U-matic 332.0213)
- Andy's Summer Playhouse, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Artist and the Hippopotamus, Symposium, undated (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0164)
- ATM 1 & 2, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0060)
- Atra de Porta // Westlake, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0087)
- Averall Stars "Average Blues" // C-Note, 1998 (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0027)
- Band on the Run -- Wings, 1973 (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0184)
- Basic Behavior, 1982; cuid39246 (Box 1, Folder 10-11, Box 2, Folder 1, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0006, 332.0151, Box 32, Vhs 332.0234, 332.0263, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 16, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_3)
- Beep 2, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0085)
- Benefits, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Benefits -- Avant-Garde-Aroma at PS 122, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Benefits -- La MaMa, 1992, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4, Box 32, Vhs 332.0221, 332.0273)
- Benefits -- The Neu Review, 1991-1992, 1994, 1997; cuid39247 (Box 2, Folder 5, Box 31, Hi8 332.0300-332.0302, Box 32, Vhs 332.0282, 332.0288, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_4)
- Biblios Reading, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- The Big Blue (film by Andrew Horn, screenplay by Jim Neu), 1986; cuid39248 (Box 2, Folder 7-9, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0008, 332.0031, 332.0045, 332.0116, 332.0146, Box 32, Vhs 332.0289, Box Shared Fales 097, Folder 3, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_5)
- The Big Lip, 1990-1991, 2000; cuid39249 (Box 2, Folder 10-11, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0001, 332.0053, 332.0111, Box 31, Hi8 332.0202, Box 32, Vhs 332.0268, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_6)
- Bill, Deborah, Jim at La Roe // Bill, Clio, Jerry at Dicks, 2003 (Box 28, Audiocassette 332.0003)
- Bill Rice, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Biography and Resumes (Jim Neu), undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bird Symposium, undated (Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0112, Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0181)
- Blood on the Pumpkin, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Blue, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0114)
- Body + Soul Artbook (featuring Jim Neu), circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 4)
- A Boy, A Beer, and a Blonde, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Boy Meets Horn, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- The Brady Bunch: The Story of Cindy Brady (Christopher Knowles), undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- The Bribe, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0081)
- Brooklyn Arts and Culture Association, Inc, undated (Box Shared Fales 097, Folder 4)
- Buffalo Dreams, 1986; cuid39250 (Box 3, Folder 8-9, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0031, Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0033, Box 32, Vhs 332.0269-332.0270, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_7)
- Byrd Hoffman Foundation, 1969-1974, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Cars, undated (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0307)
- Carter, Gay 90's, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0147)
- Chance's Place or The Casablanca Variations, 1990; cuid39251 (Box 3, Folder 11, Box 32, Vhs 332.0275, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_8)
- Chez LaRoe / a theatrical salon / Beat Night / Jim Neu, 1997 (Box 32, Vhs 332.0286)
- Chicago - Summer 1952, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- The Chinese Room (film by Andrew Horn, screenplay by Jim Neu), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
- City, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0063)
- Clarinet 1, Psych Scene 4a, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0110)
- Closing Music Q4, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0042)
- Co-Experience, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0067, 332.0072)
- Correspondence -- Andrew Horne, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence -- Ed Leighton, 1968-1977, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
- Correspondence -- General, 1975-2010 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- Creative Capital -- Grant, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Creative Capital -- Professional Develpoment at National Performance Network (NPN), 2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Cullen, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Dark Gallery, 1981 (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0113)
- Dark Pocket, 1994, 1999; cuid39252 (Box 5, Folder 4-6, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0023, 332.0036, 332.0038, 332.0050, 332.0103, 332.0142, 332.0154, Box 32, Vhs 332.0217, 332.0261, 332.0271, 332.0280, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 17, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_9)
- Dead Men Don't Tan, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Deep Cover, 1986; cuid39253 (Box 5, Folder 8-9, Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0305, Box 32, Vhs 332.0292, 332.0298, Box 34, U-matic 332.0215, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_10)
- Dialog Dance, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Dialogs Jim Neu John Nesci, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Doomed Love, 1984, 2006; cuid39254 (Box 6, Folder 1-2, Box Shared Fales 097, Folder 5, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_11)
- Drafts, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Drill Team, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Drum Boogie (Instrumental), undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0022)
- Duet for Spies, 1985-1987; cuid39255 (Box 6, Folder 5-6, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0011, 332.0115-332.0016, 332.0157, Box 32, Vhs 332.0225, 332.0233, 332.0252-332.0253,332.0285, 332.0296, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 18, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_12)
- Echo Ranch, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 7-8, Box 7, Folder 1-3, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0068, 332.0074, 332.0101, 332.0143, Box 32, Vhs 332.0224, Box 34, Half inch audio reel 332.0299, Folder 1 Left, Flat-file-folder 1)
- Ed Leighton, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- An Evening with Jesse James, 1988, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 5-8, Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0089, 332.0097, 332.0099, Box 32, Vhs 332.0244, 332.0246, 332.0259, 332.0272, Box 33, Vhs 332.0274)
- An Evening with Jesse James, 1988, 1996; cuid39256 (Box 34, U-matic 332.0191, 332.0199, 332.0207, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 19, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_13)
- Excerpts from Various Productions (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Exodos Festival of Contemporary Performing Art (Ljubljana, Slovenia), 1999-2008 (Box 8, Folder 1, Box 31, Minidv 332.0309)
- Explosion #3, undated (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0172)
- Eye and Ear Theater, circa 1990s (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Fake Book, 1991; cuid39257 (Box 8, Folder 3-4, Box 33, Vhs 332.0226, 332.0230, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_14)
- The Floatones, 1995, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 5-6, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0014, 332.0049, 332.0118, 332.0127, 332.0171, Box 31, Hi8 332.0304, Minidv 332.0310, 332.0313, Box 33, Vhs 332.0235, 332.0241, 332.0250, 332.0265)
- The Floatones, 1995, 2002; cuid39258 (Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 20, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_15)
- Flutes 2 & 3, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0075)
- Gang of Seven, 2007-2008; cuid39259 (Box 8, Folder 7, Box 9, Folder 1, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0026, 332.0090, Box 27, Audiocassette 332.0121, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_16)
- Gertrude Lawrence and Noël Coward, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0108)
- Gertrude Stein, Napa Valley Theater co/ Michael Galasso, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0138)
- Gorilla My Love, 1995; cuid39260 (Box 34, Vhs 332.0257, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_17)
- Grants and Funding, 1994, 1999-2002 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Him or Me, 1979, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 3-6, Box 27, Audiocassette 332.0017, 332.0040, 332.0080, 332.0104, 332.0126, 332.0155, 332.0158, 332.0175, Box 34, U-matic 332.0198, Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 14)
- House of Dragons, undated (Box 9, Folder 7, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 21)
- I. Friday Jun 7th, undated (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0174)
- Ia'son, There I go, There I go, Music, Nesci/Paul G., Tape #3, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0119)
- Identity Opportunity, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0123)
- Interview with Sammy Cahn, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0025)
- Interviews and Press about Jim Neu, 1975-1999 (Box 9, Folder 8, Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 15)
- Jack Benny, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0073)
- Jazz at Turtle Bay Music School, 2010; cuid39261 (Box 10, Folder 1, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_18)
- Jim Neu, Bob Feldman's John Nesci -- Chez, 2000 (Box 33, Vhs 332.0287)
- Jim Neu Excerpts, 1986-1993 (Box 33, Vhs 332.0277, 332.0279, 332.0284)
- Jim Neu -- Ito of Beats, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0125)
- Jim Neu Obituary (Boston Globe), 2010 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- The Jim Neu Songbook, 1982-2010 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Jim Spacemen Potpourri, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0096)
- Jim Neu Vamp for Duke, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0083)
- Jim's Part, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0046)
- Johnny Griffer // David, Duke, & Pops, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0020)
- Kathy // Teddy Wilson Lester Young, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0076)
- KCR - Roy Eldridge H.B. for Carol, undated (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0176)
- Kiss Shot, 2002; cuid39262 (Box 10, Folder 4-5, Box 31, Minidv 332.0315, Box 33, Vhs 332.0264, 332.0281, 332.0294-332.0295, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 22, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_19)
- La Bayadane, Waltz in a Minor Key, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0150)
- La Vie Noir, 2007; cuid39263 (Box 10, Folder 6-7, Box 31, Sound disc-minidisc 332.0316-332.0319, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_20)
- Laundromat, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0012)
- Lenny Project, undated (Box 10, Folder 8, Box 27, Audiocassette 332.0054-332.0055, 332.0079, 332.0093, 332.0148-332.0149)
- Leonard Greycloud, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Liebestod [sp?] USA, 1/2 Tom Simpson, 1/2 Adam & Susan, 1980 (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0130)
- Live Bribe @ Dixon, 1987 (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0106)
- Live Witness, 1992-1994; cuid39264 (Box 11, Folder 1, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0023, Box 27, Audiocassette 332.0078, 332.0105, 332.0145, Box 33, Vhs 332.0276, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_21)
- Liz Story // Papa John Creach and Friends, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0057)
- Lizard Monitors (Cathy Weiss), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Looks Light Heartache, 1981 (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0035)
- Loverman, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Mag (Magazine with Jim Neu Interview), 2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Maybe (Lyrics by Jim Neu, Music by Lenny Pickett), 1998; cuid39265 (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0024, 332.0030, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_22)
- The M.C.N. Song, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0039, 332.0064)
- McKinney's Cotton Pickers, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0051)
- Media Business Recycled Tape for 10/13 shoot, 1979-1980 (Box 34, U-matic 332.0204)
- Mike Galasso, undated (Box 27, Audiocassette 332.0061, 332.0137)
- M-J-Q Inker //Amos & Andy, 1984 (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0019)
- Mondo Beyondo, 1997; cuid39266 (Box 11, Folder 5, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0028, 332.0032, 332.0082, 332.0092, 332.0165-332.0166, 332.0180, Box 31, Hi8 332.0303, Box 33, Vhs 332.0222, 332.0227-332.0229, 332.0238, 332.0240, 332.0260, 332.0293, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 23, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_23)
- Moon Over Neptune (film by Jacob Burkhardt, screenplay by Jim Neu), 2008 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- M.O.R. (Middle of the Road), 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 7, Box 12, Folder 1-2, Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0059, Box Shared Fales 093, Folder 15)
- Movie Music, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0047, 332.0052)
- Mutual Narcissism, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 3-6, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0001, 332.0053, Box 27, Audiocassette 332.0048, 332.0135, Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 16)
- Mutual Narcissism, 1984; cuid39267 (Box 33, Vhs 332.0266, Box 34, U-matic 332.0197, 332.0205, 332.0208, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_24)
- Napa Valley Theater Company (NVTC) Experimental Theater -- Citizens Arrest, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Napa Valley Theater Company (NVTC) Experimental Theater -- Heartland, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Napa Valley Theater Company (NVTC) Experimental Theater -- One Nite Only, 1975-1976, 1997; cuid39268 (Box 19, Folder 2, Box 33, Vhs 332.0219, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_25)
- Napa Valley Theater Company (NVTC) Experimental Theater -- Riding the Right Horse, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 3, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 24)
- National Performance Network (NPN) - Iowa, 2004-2005 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Neal Kirkwood, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 8, Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0131)
- New Work - by Jim Neu, Recorded live at the Currican Theatre - N.Y.C, 1998 (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0177)
- Noir Mechanics, 1996, 2011-2012 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Notebook #1, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Notebook #2, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Notebook #3, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Notebook #4, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Notebook #5, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Notebook #6, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Notebook #7, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Notebook #8, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Notebook #9, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Notebook #10, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Notebook #11, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Notebook #12, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Notebook #13, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Notebook #14, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Notebook #15, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Notebook #16, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Notebook #17, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Notebook #18, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Notebook #19, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Notebook #20, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Notebook #21, 1982-1991 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Notebooks, undated (Box 17, Folder 2-4, Box 18, Folder 1-3)
- Notecards with Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Off (unfinished play), undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Oneosaph, 1981, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 6-8, Box 34, U-matic 332.0212, Box 35, U-matic 332.0187, 332.0193-332.0195)
- The Optimismo Lounge, 1991; cuid39269 (Box 20, Folder 1-2, Box 26, Audiocassette 332.0045, Box 27, Audiocassette 332.0018, 332.0021, 332.0070, 332.0098, 332.0136, 332.0139, 332.0144, Box 28, Audiocassette 332.0159-332.0160, 332.0163, 332.0168-332.0170, 332.0179, 332.0185, Box 33, Vhs 332.0223, 332.231, 332.0251, 332.0256, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_26)
- Orchestral Sounds for movie-like background, unedited version, motel scene, Lenny Pickett, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0133)
- Original Songs by Jim Neu, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Otrabanda Company, Roger Babb and Jim Neu, 1992 (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0173)
- Personal Calendars, 1981, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Perverse City Part I Subway, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0100)
- Play X, 1998 (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0153)
- Portrait of Jim Neu, undated (Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 17)
- Promotional Materials for Performances, 1986-2010 (Box 20, Folder 5, Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 18)
- Q3 Slides, Rhythm Section with Bass Flutes & Saxophone, Tape #2 Dialogue Begins, Tape #4, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0107)
- Queen Teen, undated (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0141)
- ラインの黄金, Rain no Ōgo, undated (Box 29, Audiocassette 332.0013)
- Rat Song, undated; cuid39270 (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0122, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_332_ER_27)
- Rehearsal Tapes, undated, 2002 (Box 30, Audiocassette 332.0140, 332.0161-332.0162)
- Research Materials -- Duke Ellington, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 6, Box 28, Audiocassette 332.0056, 332.0178, Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 19)
- Research Materials -- Films and Cowboys, 1997-2007 (Box 20, Folder 7, Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 20)
- Research Materials -- Films and Cowboys -- The Lone Ranger, undated (Box 31, Audiocassette 332.0203)
- Research Materials -- Jazz, 1985-2005 (Box 20, Folder 8, Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 21-22)
- Research Materials -- Jesse James, 1988, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 1, Box Shared Fales 096, Folder 23)
- Reviews and Press Packets, 1978-2009 (Box 21, Folder 2-3, Box Shared Fales 043, Folder 25)
- Rhythm Track, undated (Box 28, Audiocassette 332.0007)
- Roy, undated (Box 28, Audiocassette 332.0065, 332.0095)